<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>research on Florian Oswald</title>
    <link>https://floswald.github.io/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in research on Florian Oswald</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 10:57:27 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://floswald.github.io/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hedonic Housing over the Lifecycle</title>
      <link>https://floswald.github.io/project/hedonic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 10:57:27 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://floswald.github.io/project/hedonic/</guid>
      <description>In this project we want to build an empirical lifecycle model with the following features:
 2D location choice choice of housing quality index choice of mortgage size choice of liquid savings choice of whether rent vs own  We directly refer to our companion paper when thinking about housing supply: It is impossible to rent a 5 bedroom apartment in the suburbs. Similary, it is relatively expensive to buy a 4 bedroom flat in the very city center.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airbnb vs Rents</title>
      <link>https://floswald.github.io/project/airbnb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 23:15:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://floswald.github.io/project/airbnb/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s the causal impact of airbnb listings on long-term rents and house prices? In this project we try to establish a causal link between the two by using proprietary airdna data together with detailed rental market listings.
Status Data Theory: We have a simple model to motivate the estimation Data Analysis: We wanted to use terrorism as a demand shifter for airbnb tourism demand, didn&amp;rsquo;t work. currently looking for alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fertility and Location Choice in the City</title>
      <link>https://floswald.github.io/project/fertility/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 23:15:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://floswald.github.io/project/fertility/</guid>
      <description>In this project we want to better understand the role of fertility choices in the context of the standard Urban Model. How many children will be born in each location? Why is fertility different across cities? What is the role of fertility for city growth, over and above migratory flows alone? How could the literature on fertility think for so long about long run trends without considering the impact of children on the equilibrium house price?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>